<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on barakyo</title>
    <link>https://barakyo.github.io/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on barakyo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://barakyo.github.io/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2019 New Year Resolutions</title>
      <link>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2019-01-12-2019-new-year-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2019-01-12-2019-new-year-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I know I&amp;rsquo;m a little late to this, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had these resolutions for a while. I just feel like documenting them and putting them somewhere will hopefully make me more accountable. In addition to posting them somewhere to increase accountability, I need to revise some of these goals so that they&amp;rsquo;re more specific and measurable. I&amp;rsquo;d like to review myself each month to keep track of my progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Resolutions - One Month Review</title>
      <link>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2015-02-01-resolutions-one-month-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2015-02-01-resolutions-one-month-review/</guid>
      <description>Wow! I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s February already! As I stated in my New Year Resolutions post, I wrote down my resolutions so that I could be held accountable for them. Reviewing my resolutions after a year seemed like I would easily lose touch/sight of them. I decided a good idea would be to review my progress month-by-month, so here it goes:
Read more (and not programming/technical books) I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a good job of this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Ready Player One</title>
      <link>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2015-01-28-review-ready-player-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2015-01-28-review-ready-player-one/</guid>
      <description>With keeping up on my new year resolutions, the first book of 2015 that I decided to read was Ready Player One by Ernest Cline. I found the book browsing through Barnes and Nobles and realized it was surprisingly cheap on the Google Play Bookstore (sorry local Barnes and Nobles, have to justify my Nexus 7 purchase somehow).
I have to say that I hope the rest of the books I read this year are this good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 New Year Resolutions</title>
      <link>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2014-12-31-new-year-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2014-12-31-new-year-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>Well I hope I&amp;rsquo;m not too late to get my new year resolutions in. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this post for a while, but was only finally inspired after my last cup of coffee of 2014. In fact, this day included a lot of lasts. The last swim of the year, the last time I&amp;rsquo;d visit my brother in 2014, the last time I&amp;rsquo;d accidentally cut myself in 2014 (I hope), the last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 years, 5 months, and 14 days</title>
      <link>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2014-10-02-25-years-5-months-14-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2014-10-02-25-years-5-months-14-days/</guid>
      <description>Today I am 25 years, 5 months, and 14 days old, the exact same age my brother was when he passed away. This day has been on my mind everyday for the past year. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent long car rides, sleepness nights, and countless laps swimming thinking about today, asking my self what should I do, what should I say. After wrestling with my thoughts, I thought it may be best to write out my thoughts and reflect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Barakyo?</title>
      <link>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2013-11-12-why-barakyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barakyo.github.io/post/2013-11-12-why-barakyo/</guid>
      <description>Over this past weekend I was asked, twice, &amp;ldquo;Why Barakyo?&amp;rdquo; While the explanation is simple enough, I sometimes get the response that my Barakyo nickname isn&amp;rsquo;t professional. I&amp;rsquo;ve even been told I should consider choosing another domain name. While I understand that my nickname isn&amp;rsquo;t professional and even though I share my blog with companies that I am interested in, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to strip my blog of me, hence the reason for the personal category.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
